Bird Treader: Sakaguchi
What's a "Sakaguchi"?
You have a last name?
Isn't that great? He has a last name?
So you're Mr. Sakaguchi.
His last name is...
Sakaguchi Tori no Treadmouth.
What? Maybe I got it wrong.
But, well...
It's the same with names of living things.
It's all for human convenience, isn't it?
You know, weeds, fish... if you sit on them, they don't taste good... if you eat them.
It's just that they don't taste good.
"Small fry." That's terrible, pedal.
It's true. And it's used in bad language.
You're a small fry! That's right.
That's right.
No, "weed" doesn't mean it's a weed.
Let's give it a name.
I'm sure it exists.
Maybe it's a scientific fact.
I guess so.
Everyone only cares about beautiful flowers.
I don't think that's right.
Bokar.
I, I, Iker, I'll kill you. That's a treat for humans, really.
But you were saying... there's sansai soba (buckwheat noodles with edible wild plants).
Sansai soba (buckwheat noodles with edible wild plants)... are quite expensive.
Sansai used to be a weed that grew in the mountains.
So...
An elderly lady told me that during the war, when there was no food, she had to go to the mountains and eat them.
I mean, it's not a trauma, but... they were eating them in the backyard.
So weeds can become a luxury item.
Now that I've said all that...
So, the Sakaguchi Bird's Pudding Yamazaki Spring Bread Festival is here
Let's try Maruko first.
Sakaguchi Tori no Fundamashi
Just a little fluff.
It's a bit of a sentiment theme.
It's like bird feces.
The impact is incredible, isn't it?
I don't like it, it looks like something I'd see in a dream, but it's a little scary.
I'd be scared if I saw one of those around.
It's full of brains, even if it's just a little bit.
Smart, isn't he? - Yes, he is.
Like a bird. A bird.
Yes, sir...
It's the same idea.
I drew the bird just as an afterthought.
But the main body is here.
The bird is cool.
A bird?
This is the bird.
Is this the one with the soul?
It's the poop soul.
It looks like bird poop.
It's not a tadpole.
What was it?
It's...
Why is the one that goes into the "Shite-kekkai" so bad? I thought it might be an inn hunter...
I'm not sure if this bird is good or not, but it's really good!
You know, it's better to write this on the side...
It's better than the main mouth.
It's like she's dropping a huge bomb... and it looks like bird droppings... which, by the way... is very, very close.
By the way, it's too bad. It's not a lodestar. It's a spider.
It's a tiny spider. I made it bigger.
How should I put it?
The color is also catchy. I only had black magic markers.
It's an orange, or a reddish orange.
It was a bright color, like a reddish orange or a yellowish orange.
And it's probably 7 to 9 mm, so I guess it's about the same size.
It's very tiny.
So, for example, if you see it on a leaf or a tree, you might mistake it for bird droppings.
So it's a cloud of the "fluff fluff fluff" type.
It's the first time I've heard of this genre.
It's like a trick cloud. It's like a biker gang's cloud.
It's like a biker gang's "hello" kind of thing.
I mean, you know, we humans have titles like "something-something" or "something-something" or "something-something" or "something-something" or "something-something" or "something-something" or "something-something" or "something" or "something" or "something.
There's a way of dividing them, and it's amazing.
Kogane Unjo?
I wrote it myself.
It's long
He'd have a hard time making business cards, wouldn't he?
I'm like this, sir.
Like a kuwamoku.
By the way, when you say "cloud," I'm a little scared.
They're very small, beautiful and cute.
I see.
It's like a beautiful stone.
It's something that's very popular among spider enthusiasts.
I hear it's very popular. Oh, my. Cloud mania.
Wow, there's a Sakaguchi bird stepping on it! Like that.
So it's that good, huh?
It seems to be a good thing.
Well, well, well.
Well, let's see...
Scary! I'm a little scared now, seeing it myself!
But Mariko dreams, too, by herself.
It's a little scary.
I'll see it myself. What the hell! Scary! Scary!
What is it?
I'm afraid of that expression.
I'm scared...
I'm really scared!
I'd like to hear from you.
I'm afraid I'm not going to be able to pull it off.
Good evening, live audience!
Good evening, everyone!
I'll try to fix it, but I've also been thinking of God...
Oe, I noticed that very well.
Oe, I'm so glad you noticed!
320 yen.
And Mariko is too cute!
Bon appétit!
What's with you guys?
You can't say that here.
You can't say that to my face.
Nice way of putting it.
Say it to my face.
Mariko is cute in November.
Hey, that's not good?
I'm sure they'll say it, if you're a fan.
After all, it's nice to be told, isn't it, girls?
I'm glad.
Let's say it next time.
When is the next time?
So, here we are,
Today, I'd like to share a little bit of everything with the live audience.
I have a big announcement.
I have a big announcement to make.
May I have your attention, please?
First of all, I would like to make an annual announcement.
First of all, we are going to have our annual event,
This year, we are going to hold the annual "Odate Uchidevil" event in the spring.
This year, the name has changed a little bit.
It will be held on February 23 next year.
It will be held on Sunday, February 23 next year.
It has changed a lot.
What?
The name has changed, hasn't it?
What a surprise!
I wonder what changed.
I was like, "How did you know?
I didn't know either.
Yes, yes, yes.
So...
It's Sunday, February 23rd, next year 2025
The show starts at 18:00
The show starts at 4:00 p.m. in the evening.
The reason why we have two hours is because...
Because there will be merchandise...
I'm sure there will be some goodies.
Ouch, ouch!
I don't like that kind of joke.
Don't do things that aren't in the script.
I was trying to copy you.
That's why
I've done a lot of things this time.
Please.
We've put a lot of effort into this show.
We made a lot of goods.
A lot!
We've got a lot of stuff.
Which one do you want to start with?
You're going to introduce them?
The most gorgeous one first?
You're going to go first?
I'm going to go right off the bat, aren't I?
Towel
It's a plain towel.
It's really just that plain, plain towel.
It's really just a plain towel.
The most familiar towel.
It's not a luxury towel.
It's just, you know, it's got the logo of the Devil and me.
I'm going to put out a towel with my handwriting on it.
I was asked to write on it.
Is that possible?
Writing on a towel?
No, I don't.
I don't even write a single note.
So I wrote this just to say that it's really common, but it was popular to wrap a towel around your head, wasn't it?
I wrote something like this on twitter, something like a tweet.
I'm sure he doesn't know about this towel culture.
I think that's how it used to be.
I wonder why it was so popular in those days.
Young people were playing the "Toll" game, and these towels were used for that.
I'd like to go to the sauna with it
Like this...
It's a treatment! It's like that.
I don't have to explain myself anymore. Towels, I know.
What's next? Let's see, there's some actual stuff over here.
Do you have an Axta? Yes! Here it comes, here it comes, here it comes!
Okay, okay, okay, let's go.
Let's get this one and this one out.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, like this.
Oh, my God, the Axta...
There's more!
There's enough for everyone.
Well... I don't want to put too many on the shelf...
I see... Yes...
It's not the tomb of the first emperor, right?
It's full of people.
It's just like that.
It's an annual event.
And have you seen the badge?
Can badge?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
I'm so happy, I'm so happy
Like this one?
Yes, this one is cute, too.
It's quite big.
A mask? Looks like a mask.
Masks?
I don't know any masks.
I know mentsuko.
You do? You know what a mask is?
Boom!
What? How did you know?
Boom! Boom!
That's a Showa-era game.
We cried together once.
Even in the Heisei era, they still do it.
It's like the old elementary school game. What were the rules?
Don't they usually put the first mask on the table and play "ah-ha"? Imagery.
You hit something with your masks, and if it flips over, you win.
Or if it goes under. If it goes under, you win?
No, no, no, it's easier than turning it over.
You can do it like this, like this.
So the most important thing is to think of it as a technique.
Then, with this wind pressure, you'll float.
Don't talk about masks. Don't talk about masks.
Master's badge is so cool!
I don't know... it's like we're all doing this pose with these cheekbones.
The photographer said, "Let's do a pose.
What is it like? Isn't it really cool? The master's.
See? It's got a certain sex appeal.
He's like a writer. A novelist, for sure.
Like he won the Akutagawa Prize. Double winner. Also won the Naoki Prize.
It's pretty big.
I'd love to see you mingle with him.
Don't do it.
And this.
May I have Marco put it on?
Oh! Here it is!
What is this place? A wrist?
Wristband... like a penlight.
It glows.
Wristband lights?
LED wristbands.
LEDs!
LEDs make everything come true, right?
LEDs.
Yes, that's right.
If it's red, it's good for the skin.
I see.
With this, we want everyone to be excited at the concert.
You know, you can communicate with various people with this.
Also, you can do your shopping at vending machines.
It can be used anywhere in the country.
That's great, Devil.
Don't blame me. You don't need a wallet and credit cards.
That's all you need.
What?
We don't have that feature. Can we have it on our own?
No?
In this age of 2022...
Not even that?
I don't get it. I don't get it.
You mean something that glows.
It just glows.
No, no, no.
Just glows.
Can we call it just glows?
Just glowing.
You're not really here to advertise, are you?
You're really here to advertise, aren't you?
Yes, yes, yes.
And then...
That one, by the way.
Of course...
I also have the ones from various people like this.
Here it is...
It's like this.
And of course, there are also acstas...
And the badges, too.
We also have a complete set of acrylic stands.
All in one set?
That's right.
I see.
Shouldn't there be a complete set of acrylic stands and badges?
That's fine.
If you can't do that, you should put a lot of stuff on it.
I really want to put them on!
So...
Did you put it on yesterday?
No, no, not yesterday.
We have a lot of goods, so if you buy them all together for 10,000 yen or more...
you get a poster as a special bonus.
Wow!
Not this one?
Oh, that one!
Oh, you mean like the Seiko Matsuda poster I used to have in my room?
The silhouette one? The silhouette poster. You get a rare poster like that?
I found it at my parents' house, but the paper was a little deteriorated, so it didn't spread properly.
It's all falling apart. It's not that bad.
Is that okay? You don't give up? Don't you want it? Posters are included with purchases over 10,000 yen.
Thank you. And...
This is bad, this is bad, this is bad.
Oh, no, no, no, no...
If it's this!
Yay!
So this time, I made the Kytunken-don...
Here, I made some.
It comes with a bamboo whisk. Yay!
It says "Kyu-tong-ken" on it.
This is awesome!
And on the bottom of the bowl...
At the bottom of the bowl, there's a message from me.
That's right.
I think that's what it means. Do you know what it means that you can't understand this abyssal world unless you drink up the soup? You know what I mean?
If you don't drink all of it, it's a connection. It's the deepest, most abyssal world.
Oh, no...
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
I don't get it. That's why the master wrote the note.
Yes, this is my handwriting, or rather, I really wrote it.
So you can see the abyss.
Made in Abyss
I want to eat ramen noodles with this... and this red and black is so cool... isn't it?
I'm so glad you finally made a donburi!
I'm glad you're here, thank you very much.
I'm so glad you're pleased with it.
It's a rare scene random trading clear card!
I've got the 4-dimensional point that Doraemon just gave me...
Say it
That's amazing!
So here it is
Let's take one...
Here you go
Let's take a look.
I think it's easier to see this.
Here you go.
It's from Balico.
I don't think this is the program that aired.
Yes, sir.
It's a clear card of the scene.
Oh, wow!
Maricar will want this.
Hakata vs.
Nice smile.
There's something a little cool about him again.
There's something about this fist feeling.
No, really.
Like this.
For example...
This one...
Is it me?
Say, "Where is this?
I like it.
Is this a quote?
Give me a break... some people really want this...
Yes...
Yes... 36 kinds of these...
What?
This is yours, but it's mine?
My dad never called me an idiot.
I never thought this would become a product.
Like this?
It's random, isn't it?
Really full of them
A set of two kinds
I don't have any of the three of us here right now.
Actually, can I?
Yes, sir.
It's like this.
Random trading clear cards of famous and unusual scenes. They're the perfect size to put in the back of your cell phone, right?
It's about the same size as a regular trading card.
It's a balicata.
I'm sure there's something nostalgic about it... we do a lot of moving around.
You're just sitting there. You look like an idiot.
It's good for a gag, right?
This is so funny!
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
And this is a celebration for all of you.
Of course, we receive various congratulatory gifts and purchases from our customers, but this is a trading card.
The trading card with our autograph on it.
Of course, we'll be autographing them, and they'll be included in the package.
So if you buy it, you'll be able to have it with you when you buy it.
I hope you'll think that when you buy it... there's not many of them, right?
Wow, what a great card game you're watching!
I'm looking at some cards...
I'm in.
Arc's that!
What's this? Wait a minute.
Wait a minute... it can't be here...
Drover! I'm sorry, I just put it over here.
Thank you very much. On the back?
On the front. What? Three sheets. You mean all three?
It's a waste of time.
He's so excited that it's signed.
Really? Really?
Okay, you'll all write on them later, so there's one for each of you.
Where should I write it? There.
For example, here's a sample.
Oh, nice.
And I'm done. You're early.
I wrote it. I wrote it.
Let's see the comments. Thank you very much.
It's like we're all writing. We all write.
It's so rare!
I'm done, sir!
Don't rattle your signature. I'm not used to writing my own signature.
Is that so? You wrote beautifully.
See?
What rattling signature? I shake.
What's a master's signature? Indeed...
He wrote his face on the towel.
That's right, that's right, that's the face of the design.
Like this.
He's so happy!
It's nice.
So cute!
Mariko, can I see it again? Yes.
You know, from a distance, your signature looks like a gung-ho gal.
You know what I mean? Gungoro Gyaru.
It's like the Heisei Era.
Yes, I see it.
Like this, the one I just did will be included.
When you buy it at random, you'll get it in the box.
I'm so glad I got it when I bought it at random.
What should we do with these? They're not dry yet. Let's put them aside.
Yes, there are 3 for each member. So there are 36 kinds in total.
So there are 36 kinds in total. And when you buy one, you get two.
Yes, yes, yes!
This is it!
It's the end of the line, isn't it?
It's the end, isn't it?
This is made to order!
Made to order
It's a four-letter idiom.
Yes, it's a four-letter idiom for "made-to-order.
That means...
If you miss this period, you can't buy it.
You can't buy it.
Four-letter word.
It's a 4-letter word.
Yes, well, that's it.
That's all I have to say.
That's it.
Well, that's it. It's made-to-order.
We're taking orders right now.
Please, be the first to order!
We're streaming it live, so let's do this first.
Yes, yes...
Why don't you just do this?
Yes!
We'll do it a lot.
A lot.
You all have multiple computers, don't you?
That's right.
At least 3 computers
At least three.
With your face.
We all have at least 100 accounts.
So many accounts.
You have all kinds of accounts, like Hiroaca.
I'd love to see them.
And the photo I showed you earlier...
That's the towel.
It really is.
It's got a gift wrapping paper on it.
And the glowing one. It doesn't have any new features.
It just glows. It glows.
You should name it "just glows," not "LED wristband.
That way, it's easier to understand.
When you say "LED," you think there's something more futuristic.
Because it just glows.
So you call it just glowing? It feels like it's glowing.
It looks really shiny.
And, Masaki-san's rice bowl... I already told you that, so does that mean I can have this? Poster
Isn't this amazing? This is the visual for the Devil Festivals at the museum.
It looks like a rock band.
It's like a rock band design.
They all look amazing.
They all fit together nicely.
The balance is really good.
You're right.
Master.
You're so funny!
Anyway, he's really trying to get laughs, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
Well, well, well, well, well, well, well...
Well, then, Devil's Festivus in the pavilion.
It's on the 23rd of February.
And the tickets for the show...
Tickets are now being accepted.
You are?
Until the 15th of December.
We've got 66 more days to go as Ibisu Junior High School.
Yes, 66 more...
And, of course, Aiko Takano... and Ms. Takaneko...
And Karen Tsuchiya will appear, so it's like a festival.
It's a festivals, right?
It's a festival. It's a festival. It's hard to say, but it's a festival.
So this is how it's going to be.
I know, I know, I know. Anything left to say?
That's enough. You're full?
If you say so, then I'm full.
So... here we are.
This has nothing to do with the festival, but... Mariko... you know, the Seibon Festival was here, right?
It was your birthday, wasn't it?
Do you remember receiving anything from the show?
No. I see.
Well, let me try again.
I'm a little off. But yes.
I'm glad.
Oh, wow!
I wonder what's in it.
I'm in TV sports, so I'm a TV guy.
It's always something, I don't know? It's something, yeah. It's Nike-ish.
It's in a box. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Let's open it. What is it?
What's that? There's no heavy box.
Congratulations!
What's this? Well, well, well...
It's okay. Three lines of triumph.
I miss the three lines more than ever...
This is good, this is good, this is good, this is good, this is good, this is good, this is good, this is good, this is good, this is good
I'll take the limited collection...
It's a nice thing, isn't it?
I'm talking about this shape in Adidas...
Reverse reverse.
I see... I see...
Good, good, good, good, good.
Good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good, good.
Cute!
Oh, it's cool.
Oh, my God, from the face.
Cute.
Cute!
Adidas is so cool!
Oh, wow!
That's a samba!
Samba?
It's very popular.
Samba.
It's so cute!
Hey...
I've never seen a samba with this color.
It's so cute! Delicious!
Start with the noodles.
At a bar, you'd just get into a fight.
At a bar, you'd get into a fight, but you don't start with the noodles.
In a bar, yes...
Thank you so much!
I'm flattered.
Well, I'll just put it away for now.
Is this how it's done?
Yes, sir.
It's coming together really well.
This is a perfect fit.
Tamamin is holding a Devil Festival at the museum.
and mariko happy birthday
Thank you very much!
I've received a lot of comments from people who are cracking up!
Thank you so much!
Well, well, well, well... but if you take a look at this bag...
TVK is the color of this image.
Light blue, indeed.
And light blue.
You have good taste.
If you think about it.
Yes, it is.
Well, well, well.
Like this, but with feet. You've certainly got the right size feet.
Oh, yes, indeed, indeed.
When did you check them?
Measured?
Measured! Aren't you afraid?
Not directly.
Mariko won't know.
I'm scared. I'm scared.
That's great.
Or something after Mamiko walks.
Like dinosaur footprints.
You know the kind of footprints they leave behind?
Like your footprints.
They're a little soft.
If you use that...
If you measure it...
Subtract the size of the shoe.
I see.
I'll do it.
Why don't you ask the manager?
It's the quickest and most accurate way.
I'll take that as a yes.
Okay, then.
Okay.
That didn't take long.
So, well, there were a lot of announcements today...
Yes...
In short, there will be a Cannabis Festival War next February.
Cannabis Reifest War is coming up next February.
So, please keep that in mind.
I'm sure you'll all be thinking about it.
So, what should we do?
It's until the 15th, right?
So that's it.
See you next week for the live broadcast?
Yes, Saturday at 20:00.
At 8:00 p.m.
See you next week. See you this week. Oh, and one last thing from Mariko, since we're here.
I'm going to do my best to be Mariko for 24 years.
Festival? Festival? Please come to the festival!
I'll forget December 15th, so please do it now!
So please do it now!
So, that's all for now. See you all next week for the live broadcast.
Thank you very much for your time this week.